# RICHARD HENDRIKS

PROGRAMMER



## **ABOUT**

NEWELL ROAD
PALO ALTO, CA 94303

RICHARD.HENDRIKS@PIEDPIP ER.COM

(912) 555-4321

■ PIEDPIPER.COM

SILICONHBO

**f** SILICONHBO

SILICONHBO

## WEB DEVELOPMENT

#### **MASTER**

HTML CSS

**JAVASCRIPT** 

# COMPRESSION

#### **MASTER**

MPEG MP4

GIF

# LANGUAGES

**ENGLISH** (NATIVE SPEAKER)

## **INTERESTS**

#### **WILDLIFE**

Ferrets Unicorns

## SUMMARY

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **PIED PIPER**

CEO/PRESIDENT

04/2014 - PRESENT

01/2012 - 01/2013

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores ™ that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

## **HOOLI** 01/2013 - 04/2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Worked on optimizing the backend algorithms for Hooli

#### **VOLUNTEER**

## **CODERDOJO**

**TEACHER** 

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

## **EDUCATION**

## **STANFORD**

06/2011 - 01/2014

B.S COMPUTER SCIENCE GPA 4.0

- DB1101 Basic SQL
- CS2011 Java Introduction

## **AWARDS**

## DIGITAL COMPRESSION PIONEER AWARD

TECHCRUNCH

There is no spoon.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## VIDEO COMPRESSION FOR 3D MEDIA

10/2014

HOOLI

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

## REFERENCES

**66** It is my pleasure to recommend Richard. That is all.

- ERLICH BACHMAN